Scientific name -- Sus Scrofa
Size -- 150-300 lbs. for males
Diet -- roots, bulbs, nuts, small animals, carrion

The European wild boar feeds on roots, bulbs, tubers, nuts, turnips, corn and potatoes. They will sometimes eat larvae, small animals and carrion.

The domestic pig is a direct descendant of the boar, and like pigs, boars wallow in mud to keep cool. Boar herds usually consist of sows. Males are solitary or found in small groups, except during the breeding season. 

Sows generally have one litter per year of 5-10 piglets, and are dedicated mothers. Sows are generally more aggressive than the males except during the rut. All adult boars are dangerous because of their large size and tusks, but generally won't attack unless provoked.