Scientific name -- Gallus gallus
Size -- 5-6 lbs.
Diet -- seeds and insects

Chickens have been eaten for thousands of years. While the Romans developed the first distinctive breed of chickens, ancient records show Asian jungle fowl were raised in China as early as 1400 BC. Since that time, chickens have become the most widespread and abundant domestic animal on the planet and one of the least expensive sources of protein. In addition to their meat, chickens provide eggs. In some modern African countries, 90 percent of households own scavenging chickens.