Age -- 35
Homeland -- Scyros
Occupation -- Hero of the Trojan War

A great warrior and Greek champion in the Trojan War, he was nearly invulnerable, having been dipped in the River Styx as a child by his mother, Thetis. During the dipping, however, he had been held by the tendon in one of his heels (the Achilles tendon). Following an argument with Agamemnon, leader of the Greeks outside Troy, Achilles refused to fight and the war began to go in Troy’s favor. A friend donned Achilles’ armor hoping to re-inspire the Greeks, but he was slain by the Trojan champion, Hector. Enraged, Achilles rejoined the fight, slew Hector, and dragged his body around the city. Guided by the gods, Paris of Troy hit Achilles in his heel with a poisoned arrow, and the great warrior died.