Age -- 24
Homeland -- Atlantis (now at the bottom of the ocean)
Occupation -- Warrior and soldier

Kastor, now an adult, is following in his father, Arkantos's, footsteps. He is embittered by the loss of his parents in his childhood. His mother was killed by pirates when he was very young and his father disappeared after saving the world from the machinations of the sea god Poseidon. Kastor, believes his father lives, he cannot explain why, but knows that one day he will see him again. Until that time, however, he is on his own and takes little counsel but his own.