Laborers form the basis of your economy. Make sure you have enough to generate a steady inflow of resources, but remember they are weak in combat. Have your Laborers build <link="proto:Monument">Monuments</link> to generate <link="topic:Favor">Favor</link>. Have your <link="proto:Pharaoh">Pharaoh</link> empower foundations or buildings to make your Laborers build or gather faster.

Farming and laboring peasants made up the bulk ancient Egypt’s population. They provided the surplus of food, raw materials, and manufactures that supported the ruling pharaohs, the civil bureaucracy, the priesthood, and the army. Although the life of the peasants was not easy, they lived better than peasants elsewhere due to the bounty of the Nile Valley. Peasants worked the fields, maintained the extensive irrigation system, and labored on huge public works like the pyramids, temples, and other monuments.